David Strouk

Lead Full Stack Engineer with 8 years of experience and high-level proficiency in Python, JS (Node.JS, React). Self-taught learner, driven professional with a broad set of technical skills. Main interests: Web technologies, development of SaaS products, and blockchain technology.

Lead Full Stack Engineer
Tel Aviv, Israel
058-600-0197
davidstrouk@gmail.com
davidstrouk.github.io

EXPERIENCE

AI21 Labs, Tel Aviv — Senior Full Stack Engineer

2023 - PRESENT

Working on the development of an AI-based writing companion (Wordtune), as part of the writing engineering team.

Hyro AI, Tel Aviv — Engineer Team Lead

2021 - 2023

Hired, trained and led an Agile team of 4 full-stack developers, working closely with Product Manager and Designer.

Responsible for the development of customer-facing products - SaaS for adaptive communications platforms and web widgets.

Established efficient workflow processes, monitored daily productivity, and reviewed code and architecture decisions.

Hyro AI, Tel Aviv — Full Stack Developer

2020 - 2021

Worked on implementing and improving the NLU engine of the company, based on functional programming principles.

Researched and implemented the configurability of the different skills and building blocks per customer.

Superfly Insights, Tel Aviv — Full Stack Developer

2018 - 2020

Building infrastructure for big data parsing, storage and easy access (Python, Pandas, AWS).

Tackling challenging architectural and scalability issues in DB (PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS Athena).

Built end-user applications from scratch, both Frontend (Vue.js) and Backend (Flask/Django, DBs) development.

SKILLS

Day-to-day: Node.JS, React, Python, JS, MongoDB, SQL, K8s.

Academic: C/C++, Java.

AWARDS

Bitcoin Hackathon - Tel Aviv 2018 - Poker game based on the Bitcoin Lightning Network. Won 3rd Place.

End Incitement Hackathon – Jerusalem 2017 – in partnership with the Israeli Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Goal was to find algorithmic solutions against incitement targeting Israel and Jewish people on social networks.

Facebook Challenge 2017, Tel Aviv.

Facebook Tel Aviv 2016 Hackathon.

LANGUAGES

Hebrew (bilingual)
French (mother tongue)
English (fluent)

Barrel Network, Tel Aviv — Blockchain Engineer

2018

Created a data marketplace platform based on a token cryptocurrency (JavaScript, Solidity/NEO Smart Contracts).

Student Position, Tel Aviv — *Back End Developer*

2016 - 2017

PHP development in core team.

Technion International Office, Haifa — MOOC Developer

2015 - 2016

Programmed MOOC's integration to Coursera platform.

EDUCATION

The Open University of Israel — *M.Sc*, Computer Science

2019 - PRESENT

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa — B.Sc, Computer Science

2014 - 2018

Université de Lorraine, Nancy, France — Applied Foreign Languages Bachelor

2015 - 2018

Hebrew Language Speciality